Richard Eldridge

Marietta, GA | 404-625-9574 | Email: richardaeld@gmail.com | Website: https://richardeld.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Richardaeld | LinkedIn: https://github.com/Richardaeld | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-eldridge-4200221ab/

Software Developer

Software Developer with two years of daily coding experience. Equally comfortable in front-end or back-end development. Object-Oriented Program (OOP) language specialization is JavaScript with additional skills in Python, Django, React.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, and more. Excellent written and verbal communication skills, experience working in a collaborative team environment, and strong troubleshooting skills gained from multiple hackathons and previous employment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages	Databases	Frameworks	Libraries	Version	Other
PythonJavaScriptHTML5CSS3	MongoDBPostgreSQLSQLite	DjangoFlaskExpress.js	BootstrapReact.jsKnex.js	Control Git GitHub	 Node.js Heroku Amazon Web Service (AWS) Object-Oriented Programming Google Searches

EDUCATION AND TRAINING:

May 2020 – Nov. 2021 Code Institute - Software Development Diploma

*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

PERN project with RESTful API: DM Tool | Repository | Repository (RESTful API)

May 2022

A full-stack PERN project that allows users to view a plethora of DND content and allows authorized admins to control content. **Technology used**: PERN (PostgreSQL, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), Knex.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Github, Heroku, VSCode

E-commerce Bookstore: Eldridge Music Book Emporium | Repository

Nov. 2021

A full-stack e-commerce bookstore application designed for users to search, rate, and purchase music books.

Technology used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Stripe, VSCode

Recipe Compendium: Fat Raccoon | Repository

Jun. 2021

A full-stack recipe app with a colorful and intuitive UX that allows users to upload, view, edit, and share recipes.

Technology used: Python, Flask, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku

HACKATHON PROJECTS:

Smitten: Smitten | Repository

Feb. 2022

A front-end Valentine's Day themed game designed to entertain fans of the popular application Wordle.

• This project achieved 1st place in Code Institute's, "Love is in the Air" February 2022 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, CSS | My Role: Scrum Master, Lead JavaScript Debugger

Wheelchair Accessibility Calculator App: Spinning Wheelchairs | Repository

Sept. 2021

A front-end project designed to determine if a hallway or doorway has adequate space for a wheelchair's turn radius.

This project achieved 3rd place in Code Institute's Trust in SODA 2021 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, HTML, CSS | My role: JavaScript Algebra Implementer

WORK EXPERIENCE:

SGPS ShowRig, Inc., Norcross, GA

Feb. 2015 - Jun. 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control | Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020

- Repaired and serviced motors and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system. Delegated responsibilities. Power and Control Technician | Feb. 2018 – Nov. 2019
- Repaired and serviced electrical equipment and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system. Department Head of Rigging | Feb. 2015 – Feb. 2018
- Learned two different P.O.S. systems and trained others. Delegated responsibilities.